PRAJAKTA SHINGAVI

Bellevue, Washington • (925) 336-5278 • pshingavi89@gmail.com

PROFILE | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/prajakta-shingavi-25a593b3 | GitHub: https://github.com/prajakta0

Clinician with hands on experience using Excel, R, MySQL, Statistics & Tableau, passionate about growing in the field of data analytics. Skilled in leveraging and translating data into useful information to drive key business decisions. Skills:

- R programming
- MySQL
- Tableau
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Basic Python

- Data Analysis
- Statistical analysis
- Exploratory data analysis
- Data Visualizations
- Data Modeling

- Clinical Terminologies
- Medical Coding
- Electronic Health Records
- Problem solving & analytical skills
- Communication & Collaboration

CAPSTONE PROJECT @ HEALTH ALLIANCE INTERNATIONAL

Women's & Child health data analysis for Health Ministry of Timor Leste

Develop program performance report by analyzing data & build interactive dashboard in Tableau for trends in mHealth program performance metrics of 13 districts for last 3 years. Using tools like **MS Project, VBA, Excel, R & Tableau**.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

- **HIM Department Performance Dashboard (Excel)**: Defined KPI's & built dashboard using bar, line, pie charts & benchmarking to analyze and report key performance metrics to identify low performing departments.
- Sales Data Analysis (Tableau): Built interactive dashboard using calculated fields, hierarchies, filters, and joins to provide Business insights on store sales data of Europe across different regions in Europe.
- Instagram Analysis(MySQL): Designed & implemented relational database for Instagram likes and posts data using data modelling techniques and conducted ad-hoc analysis to extract data from the database using complex queries.
- **Finance Data Analysis (R):** Performed data cleaning, manipulation, analysis and visualization for publication of Business report on list of Fortune 500 companies and provided insights using scatterplots, boxplots with ggplot in R.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Health Alliance International-Global health dept. of University of Washington (Student Assistant) July 2018 – Present

- Reconciled errors in HR databases using Pivot table & VLOOKUP in Excel.
- Identified & rectified data quality issues in employee effort estimations using Excel formulas.
- Designed Human Resources dashboard for audit for 2018, using Tableau.

Cotiviti Healthcare (Research Analyst)

Oct 2015 - April 2016

Reviewed claim denial rules for research related queries & coded clinical cases using medical coding guidelines.

Chikittsa Wellness Management Pvt. Ltd. (Manager)

Jan 2013 - Oct 2015

- Developed effective workflow procedures to optimize patient scheduling, to increase revenue & patient satisfaction.
- Provided executives with analytics as the basis for business development, expanding by 5 new clinics in 2 years.
- Diagnosed patient orthopedic conditions and recommended appropriate treatment plan for pain management.

EDUCATION

Post Baccalaureate, Health Informatics and Health Information Management *University of Washington, School of Public Health, Seattle.*

Expected 15 June, 2019

Courses: Health Data Analytics, Health Data Management, Health Research Design & Statistics, Finance Concepts etc.

Bachelor of Ayurveda Medicine and Surgery (Maharashtra University of Health Sciences Nasik, India)

2013

Courses: Anatomy, Physiology, Medicine, Pathology, Pharmacology, Gynecology & Obstetrics, Surgery etc.